We recently updated our Privacy Policy to reflect our current business operations and processing activities, and how Learneo processes your personal data when you sign up with one of our Services (defined below).

Please note that this is a preview of our updated Privacy Policy, effective December 19, 2024. Until then, our [current version](https://languagetool.org/legal/privacy?old=true) continues to apply. Please read our updated Privacy Policy below.

Previous LanguageTool Privacy Policy (available [here](https://languagetool.org/legal/privacy?old=true))

### Part One

### Part Two

Privacy Policy
==============

ⓘ Effective date: December 19, 2024

Learneo takes privacy seriously. This privacy policy describes the personal data that Learneo collects when you use a Learneo Service, the purposes for which your personal data is used, and your choices regarding its use.

When we say "['Learneo"](https://www.learneo.com/), “we” and “us,” we mean Learneo, Inc. You can learn more about Learneo on our [website](https://www.learneo.com/).

When we say "a Learneo Service", "Service", or "the Services" we mean any of the following services operated by a Learneo business:

* "[Course Hero Services](#part-two-course-hero)": Including Course Hero, Course Sidekick, College Sidekick, Nursing Hero, CliffsNotes, Bartleby, and all other [Student Brands services](http://studentbrands.com/brands).

Any capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meaning assigned to them in each applicable set of Services terms.

#### How to Read this Privacy Policy

This privacy policy consists of **two parts:**

* [Part One](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) sets out the privacy practices that apply across the Services.
* [Part Two](#part-two) sets out the privacy practices specific to a Learneo Service, including:

* Personal data collected and processed
* Additional data security measures
* Data retention practices
* Account and personal data deletion; and
* The Cookie Policy applicable to each Service.

This policy does not cover the practices of other services Learneo may own but are not discussed in this privacy policy and listed above, other companies we don't own or control, or people we don't manage.

If you have a disability, you may access this policy in an alternative format by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

PART ONE: LEARNEO PRIVACY PRACTICES
-----------------------------------

### Data Controller

#### Learneo, Inc.

When you sign up and use a Learneo Service, Learneo, Inc. is the data controller of your personal data for the purposes of delivering those Services to you (as that term is defined in each applicable set of terms) and as otherwise permitted in this privacy policy.

#### _Contact Us_

If you are subscribed to more than one Service, or you have a question or request that pertains to more than one Service and would like to exercise any of the rights under applicable privacy law, you can submit your request to Learneo, Inc. and indicate so on the request. Learneo, Inc. will process it accordingly.

For general privacy inquiries you may contact us at:

Learneo, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Compliance  
2000 Seaport Blvd, Floor 3  
Redwood City, CA 94063 USA  
866-634-9397  
[\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
GDPR/US State Privacy Laws Request Form  

EEA and UK residents may contact our EU and UK based representative regarding all requests related to data protection and privacy:

Privacy Rep Office Limited  
Attn: Learneo, Inc.  
2nd Floor, 1-2 Victoria Buildings, Haddington Road  
Dublin 4, Dublin, Ireland, D04 XN32  
[\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
Telephone number: 0035-31-6994225  

Otherwise, please contact the Learneo company relevant to your request; you can find the contact details for the relevant company below.

##### _Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services_

For privacy inquiries regarding a specific Learneo Service, please contact us as at:

###### Course Hero, Course Sidekick, College Sidekick, Nursing Hero, and CliffsNotes

* General inquiries: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* Privacy requests: [GDPR/US State Privacy Laws Request Form](https://www.coursehero.com/copyright/#/data-privacy-request-form)
* EEA and UK residents may also contact our EU and UK based representative: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### Bartleby and Student Brands Sites

* Privacy inquiries: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* Privacy requests: [Privacy Request Webform](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/6831aab6-949d-4e00-b255-f7a236519967/d083a5f1-8d74-4b01-8c32-e6ed91d7bca5)
* EEA and UK residents may also contact our EU and UK based representative: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### LitCharts

* Privacy inquiries: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* Privacy requests: [GDPR/US State Privacy Laws Request Form](https://www.litcharts.com/privacy/gdpr-request)
* EEA and UK residents may also contact our EU and UK based representative: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### Symbolab

* Privacy inquiries and requests: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* EEA and UK residents may also contact our EU and UK based representative: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### QuillBot

* Privacy inquiries and requests: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* EEA and UK residents may also contact our EU and UK based representative: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### Scribbr

* All privacy inquiries and requests: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

###### LanguageTool

* All privacy inquiries and requests: [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

#### Children's Privacy

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal data about children under 13 years of age; if you are a child under the age of 13, please do not attempt to register for or otherwise use the Services or send us any personal data. If we learn we have collected personal data from a child under 13 years of age, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 years of age may have provided personal data to us, please contact us to provide that information (see the [contact information above](#part-one-contact-information)).

If you are under the age of 16 and a resident of the EEA or United Kingdom, or under 18 and are a resident of Israel, please have your parent or guardian contact us to provide consent for processing your personal data before you attempt to register for or otherwise use the Services or send us any personal data (see the [contact information above](#part-one-contact-information)).

For LitCharts only, the following applies:

If you are under the age of 16 (or under the age of 18 and a resident of Israel), please do not attempt to register for or otherwise use LitCharts, or send any personal data using the Service. If we learn that personal data from a child under the age of 16 (or under 18 in Israel) has been provided, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 16 (or under 18 in Israel) may have provided personal data on LitCharts, please notify us directly (see the [contact information above](#part-one-contact-information)).

#### Personal Data We Collect

##### _When you use our Services_

Our Services collect different personal data when you sign up and use them. For details on the personal data that we collect and the categories of third parties with whom your personal data is shared when you use each Service, please read the relevant Part Two section for that Service.

##### _When you Report Inappropriate Content or Submit a Notice of Copyright Infringement_

When you report content on a Learneo Service utilizing the [Learneo Report Content Form](https://www.learneo.com/legal/illegal-content-notice), we will collect your contact information (including your first and last name, address, country, and email address) so that we can remain in contact with you during the process and ensure that your notice is sufficiently addressed. This information will be used to process your request and keep a record of your notice. If we receive a valid counter-notice or dispute from the uploader, your original notice (which includes your contact information) will be forwarded to the uploader.

We will not use the personal data we collected for materially different, unrelated or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.

##### _When You Communicate With Us_

When you communicate with us in written or email correspondence for any reason (such as for support, general information, or when you provide feedback), we collect your mailing or email address (as applicable) and any other personal data you may provide with your correspondence.

##### _Information That is Not Personal Data_

We may create aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data from the personal data we collect, including by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable to a particular user. We may use such aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data within Learneo and share it with third parties for our lawful business purposes, including to analyze, build and improve the Services and promote our business, provided that we will not share such data in a manner that could identify you.

#### Our Purposes: How We Use Your Personal Data

When you use any of our Services, we use the personal data we collect for the following purposes:

* _Providing and customizing the Services you use and request_
    * Providing users with the products, Services or information they request, including when you use any one of our Services or any of our combined or integrated Services that you choose to use.
    * Operating and securing the Learneo business and our Services, including utilizing shared IT and security systems, technology and infrastructure.
    * Creating and managing user accounts or user profiles for the Services, including enabling us to allow users to sign up for, and sign in and receive one or more Learneo Services at one time.
    * Providing support and assistance for the Services, including responding to customer support inquiries, notices of inappropriate content or notices of copyright infringement, and responding to data subject rights requests under applicable law.
    * Customizing or personalizing the Services, website content and communications to provide you a better experience.
    * To distribute and display your Content, which may include your username, across one or more of our Services. Unless otherwise defined in a separate Part Two section, "Content" refers only to any user generated content you post on our Services. For example, if you post a question or answer on coursehero.com, it may be distributed and displayed on another Learneo Service, and may include your coursehero.com username.
    * Conducting fraud protection activities, implementing security and debugging.
    * Carrying out other business purposes stated when collecting users' personal data or as otherwise set forth in applicable data privacy laws, such as the California Consumer Privacy Act and other US State privacy laws or the EU or UK General Data Protection Regulation.
    * Processing orders or other transactions; billing.
* _Measuring performance and improving the Services_
    * Measuring our progress towards corporate goals and key performance indicators, including gathering commercial data related to our subscription Services.
    * Improving the Services, including by:
        * When you use our Services powered by AI, using user inputs to help improve our models.
        * Learning how you use and interact with our Services, by testing, research and development, and gathering commercial data and internal analytics on your use of a Service, or those unique users that subscribe to all or more than one of our Services, and gathering internal analytics on how you engage with one Service when integrated on another Service (for example, your use of a Symbolab feature integrated within coursehero.com).
* _Marketing the Services_
    * Marketing and selling the Services, including to co-market, co-promote or cross-sell the Learneo Services (with your consent or otherwise in accordance with applicable law).
    * Showing you advertisements, including interest-based or online behavioral advertising.
* _Communicating with you_
    * Responding to correspondence that we receive from you, contacting you when necessary or requested, sending you information about the Services or about feedback that you've provided. We may use your feedback (including your name if you choose to provide it) as permitted by the license granted to Learneo in the applicable Service Terms, including in our publicly available marketing materials.
    * Sending emails and other communications according to your preferences or that display content that we think will interest you, as permitted by applicable law.
* _Meeting legal requirements and enforcing legal terms_
    * Fulfilling our legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal process (e.g., subpoenas or warrants), such as preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities.
    * Protecting the rights, property or safety of you, Learneo, or another party, including conducting fraud protection, security and debugging.
    * Enforcing any agreements with you, including the Learneo Terms of Service and applicable Service Terms for the relevant Service.

For UK and EEA residents, please see [_Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents_](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes described above.

#### Tracking Tools, Advertising and Your Choices

Learneo and our third-party providers collect information in the Services through tracking technologies, including but not limited to, cookies (small pieces of information or text files that a website sends to your computer for record-keeping purposes and is stored in a file on your computer's hard drive), web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels"), embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, fingerprinting, device recognition technologies, in-app tracking methods and other tracking technologies now and hereafter developed ("Tracking Technologies"). Further details about the Tracking Technologies we use (including the purpose for using them), interest-based advertising, your choices and how to manage cookies and do-not-track signals are below, and can also be found in each Service's respective Cookie Policy, linked in each Service's [Part Two](#part-two) section of this Privacy Policy

##### _Advertising_

We may serve ads on our Services or on external services and engage and work with Service Providers and other third parties to serve advertisements on the Services and/or on Third-Party Services. Some of these ads may be tailored to your interests based on your browsing, across time, of the Services and elsewhere on the Internet, which may include use of data from cross-device usage, sometimes referred to as "interest-based advertising" and "online behavioral advertising" ("Interest-based Advertising"), which may include sending you an ad on a third-party service after you have left the Services (i.e., "retargeting"). Our advertisers' and ad networks' use of Tracking Technologies are governed by their own privacy policies. Further details about interest-based advertising, your choices and how to manage related cookies can also be found in each Service's respective Cookie Policy, linked in each Service's [Part Two section of this Privacy Policy](#part-two).

##### _Your Cookies and Tracking Technologies Choices_

We may use Tracking Technologies to collect information about interactions with the Services, including information about your browsing and purchasing behavior. Tracking Technologies make Web-surfing and browsing easier for you by saving your preferences so that we can use the saved information to facilitate and improve your use of the Services.

* Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately. Also, tools from commercial browsers may not be effective with regard to some Tracking Technologies, such as HTML5 cookies. Please be aware that if you disable or remove these technologies, some parts of the Services may not work and that when you revisit the Services your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.
* Some App-related Tracking Technologies in connection with non-browser usage (e.g., most functionality of a mobile app) can only be disabled by uninstalling the app. To uninstall an app, follow the instructions from your operating system or handset manufacturer. Apple and Google mobile device settings have settings to limit ad tracking, and other tracking, but these may not be completely effective.
* Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a "Do Not Track" signal to online services you visit. Note, however, there is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Like many online services, we currently do not alter our practices when we receive a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," you can visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/), but we are not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this third-party information. You have the right to request information from us about the Services that currently do not respond to "do not track" mechanisms featured in any Internet browser by contacting us according to the "Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services" section above.
* Many advertisers and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and third parties participate in voluntary programs that provide tools to opt-out of such interest-based advertising such as the Digital Advertising Alliance's ("DAA") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding interest-based advertising for DAA members, visit [https://youradchoices.com/](https://youradchoices.com/), and [http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) for information on the DAA's opt-out program for mobile apps. Some of these companies also are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). To learn more about the NAI and your opt-out options for their members, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) .
* Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads. Opting out only means that those selected, participating members should no longer deliver certain interest-based advertising to you but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit these opt-out webpages, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different device or web browser or use a non-browser-based method of access (e.g., mobile app), your browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective.
* We support IAB 2009 Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising ( [https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf](https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf) ) and expect that ad networks that we directly engage to serve you interest-based advertising will do so as well, though we cannot guarantee their compliance. We are not responsible for the effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties' opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.
* In addition, we may serve ads on third-party services that are targeted to reach people on those third-party services that are also identified on one or more of our databases ("Matched List Ads"). This is done by using Tracking Technologies, or by matching common factors between our databases and the databases of the third-party services. We are not responsible for these third-party services, including without limitation their security of the data. We are not responsible for such third parties' failure to comply with your or our opt-out instructions as they may not give us notice of opt-outs to our ads that you give to them, and they may change their options without notice to us or you. For more information, please see the selling and sharing sections of the applicable State-Specific Rights section.
* If you are located in the EEA, UK or Canada, you can manage your cookie consent choices using the consent management platform on the applicable Service. If you do not wish to accept non-Essential Cookies in connection with your use of the Services or wish to withdraw your consent, you can opt out by selecting “Reject All” or by selecting "Customize" (or similarly phrased options) and changing your Cookies Preferences

##### _Session Replay Tools_

On certain pages of certain Learneo Services, we use session replay tools provided by third party service providers, including Fullstory, Inc., Amplitude Inc., and Microsoft. Session replay tools are a necessary tool for Learneo to provide our Services. These tools allow Learneo to understand user activity and content performance to help deliver and optimize our Services, find and fix performance issues, continuously improve our user's experience, and to investigate and prevent fraud and abuse. Depending on how you use our Services, our session replay tools may automatically collect the following information:

* Device-dependent data collected by your computer and web browser:
* IP address
* E-mail address including your first and last name, insofar as you have provided it to us via our Services
* Screen size of your terminal
* Device browser information and identifiers
* Geographical data (country only)
* Language for displaying our website
* User interactions
* Mouse commands (movement, position and clicks)
* Date and time of access
* Keystrokes (not for sensitive fields like passwords or credit card information)

Our session replay tools service providers use this information to evaluate your use of our Services, to compile reports on usage and to provide us similar services for evaluating our website. Our session replay service providers themselves also use third-party services (e.g. Google) to provide these services, who may store or otherwise process information that your browser transmits when you visit our certain Services (including, under certain circumstances, your IP address).

For more information about the session replay tools we use, see:

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

### _Sharing with Third-Parties_

We share your personal data with the following categories of third-parties and for the following purposes:

* With Service Providers that help us operate our Services. These third parties help us provide the Services or perform business functions on our behalf. They include:
    * Hosting, technology and communication providers
    * Security and fraud prevention consultants
    * Analytics providers that provide analytics on web traffic or usage of our Services (e.g. tools that track user clicks or how visitors found our Services)
    * Support and customer service vendors
    * Payment processors, including those listed in the applicable Part Two section for each Service. They collect your payment information necessary to process your payment and share limited payment information with us necessary to operate our Services
    * Marketing services providers
    * Identification verification service providers
* With Advertising Service Providers and Partners to Show You Ads. These third parties help us market our services and provide you with other offers that may be of interest to you. They include:
    * Ad networks (including social media ad networks)
* With Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate When Using Our Services
    * Third-party log-in services
    * Third-party services you choose to integrate with through the Services.
* To Fulfill our Legal Obligations. Third parties that carry out the activities set forth under Meeting Legal Requirements and Enforcing Legal Terms in the How We Use Your Personal Data section above.
* Business Transfers. If we undergo a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other transaction in which a third party assumes control of our business (in whole or in part), your personal data may be transferred to that third party. Should one of these events occur, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you before your information becomes subject to different privacy and security policies and practices.

Details of the categories of personal data and the third parties with whom we share your personal data that we have collected over the past 12 months may be found in the relevant Part Two section for each Service below.

### _Sharing With Government Authorities and Law Enforcement_

When you use our Services, we may access and share the personal data described in the applicable Part Two section with regulators, law enforcement, or other government agencies as required by applicable law or if we have a good-faith belief that we must do so to comply with court orders or government requests supported with legal process. We may also do so for the purposes of detecting, investigating and preventing fraud or illegal activity on our Services, and to protect the rights and safety of our users. If we share your personal information with government or law enforcement to comply with a court order or other legal process, we will notify you of that disclosure unless we are legally obligated not to do so. For information on the categories of information that may be shared for the purposes and the legal bases for doing so, see the [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) section in this Policy.

Marketing Communications
------------------------

When you register an account or subscribe to a Service, you will receive marketing communications related to Learneo's learning and productivity services as well as transactional and account-related communications, by email and as permitted by applicable law. We will collect your email address as well as other information you provide on a voluntary basis to help tailor communications to you. In any marketing communication from a Learneo Service, you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link included at the bottom of each email. You may also opt-out of receiving marketing communications at any time either through your account settings or by contacting us (see [Contact Us](#part-one-contact-us) section above). Please note that you will continue to receive transactional or account-related communications.

Data Security
-------------

We take commercially reasonable steps to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use and disclosure using appropriate physical, technical, organizational and administrative security measures based on the type of personal data and how we are processing that data.

Examples of data security measures we implement include regular security vulnerability scanning of our Services in order to make your visit to or use of our Services as safe as possible; maintaining personal data behind secured networks that are only accessible by a limited number of persons with special access rights to such systems and who are under obligation to keep the information confidential; and implementing a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal data.

You should also help protect your data by appropriately selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism; limiting access to your computer or device and browser; and signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Although we work to protect the security of your account and other data that we hold in our records, please be aware that no method of transmitting data over the internet or storing data is completely secure.

Data Retention
--------------

We will retain your personal data as described in the applicable [Part Two](#part-two) section for the relevant Service you are using.

Changes To This Privacy Policy
------------------------------

We are constantly working to grow our business and improve our Services, offer new Services and features to you, and keep up with applicable laws. For these reasons we may need to change this privacy policy from time to time. When we make material changes, we will provide you with a reasonable form of online notice of the updated policy.

Additional Terms For Canadian Residents
---------------------------------------

If you reside in Canada, the following additional terms apply. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this policy, the provision that is more protective of personal data will apply.

### _Transfers of Personal Data Outside Canada_

We may transfer your personal data within Learneo, with third party service-providers and other third parties that require such information to assist us in providing Services to you. In the course of providing these Services, your personal data may be accessed, collected, stored and processed in the U.S. or other foreign jurisdictions by Learneo or its third party service providers. Learneo and third-party service providers may disclose your personal data in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order or as otherwise required or permitted by Canadian, US, or other law (which may include disclosure to US and foreign courts, law enforcement or governmental authorities). In the case of a transfer of personal data to Learneo or third-party service providers that process or store personal data on behalf of Learneo, Learneo and/or third party recipient will have agreed to safeguard personal data and use the information only for the purpose(s) for which it has been provided.

### _Canadian Resident Rights_

Subject to applicable law, you have the right to access, update and correct inaccuracies in your personal data in our custody or control. You can request this by email or by writing to us at the contact information set out in the [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) section above. We may request certain personal data for the purpose of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to his or her personal data records.

Additional Terms For California Residents
-----------------------------------------

This section provides information in accordance with the California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA"), as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act for California residents about how Learneo handles certain personal data collected over the past 12 months. If you are a California resident, you have the rights set forth in this section. For how to exercise these rights, see the [Exercising Your CCPA Rights](#exercising-your-ccpa-rights) section. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this policy, the portion that is more protective of your personal data will apply.

### _California Resident Rights under the CCPA_

* _Access/Right to Know._ You have the right to request certain information about our collection and use of your personal data over the past 12 months, including:
    * The categories of personal data that we have collected about you.
    * The categories of sources from which that personal data was collected.
    * The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling your personal data.
    * The categories of third parties with whom we have shared your personal data.
    * The specific pieces of personal data that we have collected about you.
* _Right to Correct_. You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your personal data, depending on the type of personal data and our purposes for processing it.
* _Deletion._ You have the right to request that we delete the personal data that we have collected about you. Under the CCPA, this right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, we may need to retain your personal data to provide you with the Services or complete a transaction or other action you have requested. Please see the [Data Retention](#part-part-one-data-retention) section on our purposes for retaining limited personal data.
* _Right to Opt-Out of Certain Activities._ In some circumstances, you have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal data or the sharing of your personal data specifically for cross-contextual behavioral advertising purposes.

_Exercising Your CCPA Rights._ To exercise the rights described above, you or your Authorized Agent (defined below) must send us a request that (1) provides sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom we have collected personal data, and (2) describes your request in sufficient detail to allow us to understand, evaluate and respond to it. Each request that meets both criteria will be considered a "Valid Request ." We may deny requests that do not meet these criteria as permitted by applicable data privacy laws. You may appeal any denial by contacting us using the relevant contact information provided in Part One. . We will only use personal data provided in a Valid Request to verify your identity and complete your request. You do not need an account to submit a Valid Request. We will not charge you a fee for making a Valid Request unless your Valid Request(s) is excessive, repetitive or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that your Valid Request warrants a fee, we will notify you of the fee and explain that decision before completing your request. Please see the [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) section for where to submit a Valid Request.

_Authorized Agent._ You may authorize an agent (an "**Authorized Agent**") to exercise your rights on your behalf. To do this, you must provide your Authorized Agent with written permission to exercise your rights on your behalf, and we may request a copy of this written permission from your Authorized Agent when they make a request on your behalf.

_Non-Discrimination._ We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws (including the CCPA) with varying prices, rates or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of personal data that we receive from you.

### _Categories of Third Parties We Have Shared Your Personal Data With_

For the categories of third parties with whom a Learneo shares the personal data it collects and has collected about you over the past 12 months, please see the relevant [Part Two](#part-two) section for the Service you are using.

### _Your Rights under California's Shine-the-Light Law_

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to contact us to prevent disclosure of personal data to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes. To submit such a request, please see the [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) section above and specify "California Shine the Light Request" in the subject line.

Additional Terms For Residents of other US States
-------------------------------------------------

This section provides information in accordance with US States other than California that may now or in the future have enacted state data privacy laws, including but not limited to the Colorado Privacy Act , the Connecticut Data Privacy Act , the Delaware Personal Data Privacy Act, the Minnesota Consumer Data Privacy Act, the Montana Consumer Data Privacy Act, the Nebraska Data Privacy Act, the Indiana Consumer Data Protection Act, the Iowa Consumer Data Protection Act, the Oregon Consumer Privacy Act, the Tennessee Information Protection Act, the Texas Data Privacy and Security Act, the Utah Consumer Privacy Act, and the Virginia Consumer Data Privacy Act. For residents of these US States, this section provides information about how Learneo handles certain personal data that we have collected about you. If you are a resident of one of these US States, you have the rights set forth in this section. For how to exercise these rights, see the Exercising Your US State Privacy Rights section. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this policy, the portion that is more protective of your personal data will apply.

### _Rights under Effective US State Laws_

* _Right to Know/Access/Portability._You have the right to confirm whether or not we are processing your personal data and to access such personal data. You may request for this information to be provided to you in a readily usable format, to the extent it is technically feasible.
* _Right to Correct_. Residents in certain states have the right to correct inaccuracies in their personal data, depending on the type of personal data and our purposes for processing it.
* _Right to Delete._ You have the right to request that we delete the personal data that we have collected about you.
* _Right to Opt-Out of Certain Activities._ In some circumstances, you have the right to opt out from (i) the sale of your personal data, (ii) the processing of your personal data for purposes of targeted advertising, (iii) the processing of your personal data for profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you.

_Exercising Your US State Privacy Rights._ To exercise the rights described above, you or your Authorized Agent must send us a request that (1) provides sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom we have collected personal data, and (2) describes your request in sufficient detail to allow us to understand, evaluate and respond to it. Each request that meets both criteria will be considered a "**Valid Request** ." We may deny requests that do not meet these criteria. You may appeal any denial by contacting us; you can find the contact details for the relevant Service in the Contact Us and the Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services sections above. We will only use personal data provided in a Valid Request to verify your identity and complete your request. You do not need an account to submit a Valid Request. We will not charge you a fee for making a Valid Request unless your Valid Request(s) is excessive, repetitive or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that your Valid Request warrants a fee, we will notify you of the fee and explain that decision before completing your request. Please see the [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) section above for where to submit a Valid Request.

_Non-Discrimination._ We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under applicable US State privacy laws. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws with varying prices, rates or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of personal data that we receive from you.

Additional State Law Privacy Rights
-----------------------------------

### _Nevada Resident Rights_

If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of certain personal data to third parties who intend to license or sell that personal data. Please note that we do not currently sell your personal data as sales are defined in Nevada Revised Statutes Chapter 603A.

Complaints
----------

If you have an unresolved privacy concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, you may appeal any decision to us by contacting Learneo. You can find the contact details for Learneo and the relevant Service in the Service in the Contact Us and [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) sections above. Otherwise, please refer to your state's process for filing a complaint with the appropriate agency. [Truste Website](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request) Under certain conditions, you may also be entitled to invoke binding arbitration for complaints not resolved by other means.

If you are a European Economic Area or UK resident, please see the [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) section for where to lodge a complaint.

Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents
------------------------------------------------------------

If you reside in the European Union, Lichtenstein, Norway or Iceland (collectively, the European Economic Area or "**EEA**") or the United Kingdom, the following terms apply. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this policy, the provision that is more protective of personal data will apply.

### _Legal Basis for Use of Your Personal Data_

The personal data processed by Learneo, as described in Parts One and Two, are processed under the following legal basis:

* _Contractual Necessity:_ Learneo processes the following categories of personal data as a matter of contractual necessity, meaning that we need to process the data to perform under our product specific Service Terms with you, which enables us to provide you with the Service:
    * Profile or Contact Data
    * Payment Data
    * Commercial Data
    * Online Identifiers
    * Device/IP Data
    * Web Analytics
    * Third-Party Login Service Data
    * Demographic Data
    * Geolocation Data (approximated)
    * Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide

This includes for the purposes of:

* Providing users with the products, services or information they request.
* Providing customer support and other assistance for the Services.
* Customizing or personalizing the Services, website content and communications.
* Creating and managing user accounts or user profiles.
* Distributing and displaying your content, which may include your username, across one or more of our Services.
* Enabling users to sign up for and sign in to multiple Services at one time.
* Processing orders or other transactions; billing.
* Responding to correspondence that we receive from you, contacting you when necessary or requested, and sending you information about Learneo or the Services when requested or as permitted by applicable law.
* Enforcing any agreements with you, including our Terms of Service or Service Terms.

When we process personal data due to contractual necessity, failure to provide such personal data will result in your inability to use some or all portions of the Services that require such information.

_Legitimate Interest:_ Learneo processes personal data when it furthers its legitimate interests. This includes:

| Purposes for Processing | Legitimate Interest Relied On | Personal Data Categories |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Learning how you use and interact with one or more of our Services for the purposes of improving the Services, including testing, research, internal analytics and product development (when such processing is not performed with cookies or otherwise in a manner requiring consent). | In our interest to understand how our customers use our Services and to improve and develop our products and Services. | Profile or Contact Data, Commercial Data, Online Identifiers, Device/IP Data, Web Analytics, Demographic Data, Geolocation Data |
| To measure our progress towards corporate goals and key performance indicators, including gathering commercial data related to our subscription Services (when such processing is not performed with cookies or otherwise in a manner requiring consent). | In our interest to understand how our customers use our Services and to improve and develop our products and Services. | Profile or Contact Data Commercial Data Online Identifiers Device/IP Data Demographic Data Geolocation Data |
| Marketing and selling the Services, e.g. by email, including co-market, co-promote and cross sell Learneo Services (when such processing is not performed with cookies or otherwise in a manner requiring consent). | In our interest to market, advertise and promote our products and Services to users. | Profile or Contact Data, Demographic Data, Geolocation Data |
| Sending transactional emails and other product communications to you as our customer according to your communications preferences. | In our interest to improve our products and Services for our users, including to personalize the Service for users. | Profile or Contact Data |
| Preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities. | In our interest, and the interests of our users, to ensure the safety and security of our Services. | Profile or Contact Data Payment Data Commercial Data Online Identifiers Device/IP Data Web Analytics Third-Party Login Service Data Demographic Data Geolocation Data Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide |
| Protecting the rights, property or safety of you, Learneo, or another party. | In our interest to protect our rights and property, and the safety of our staff. It is also in our interest, and the interest of our users, to protect the rights, property and safety of our users. | Profile or Contact Data, Payment Data, Commercial Data, Online Identifiers, Device/IP Data, Web Analytics, Third-Party Login Service Data, Demographic Data, Geolocation Data, Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide |
| Detecting and preventing fraud, security, and debugging | In our interest, and the interests of our users, to ensure the integrity of our services and to detect and prevent fraudulent activity. | Profile or Contact Data, Payment Data, Commercial Data, Online Identifiers, Device/IP Data, Web Analytics, Third-Party Login Service Data, Demographic Data, Geolocation Data, Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide |
| Completion of corporate transactions. | In our interest to operate and manage our business in the event of a proposed or actual business sale. | Profile or Contact Data, Payment Data, Commercial Data, Online Identifiers, Device/IP Data, Web Analytics, Third-Party Login Service Data, Demographic Data, Geolocation Data, Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide |

* _Consent_: In some cases, Learneo processes personal data based on the consent you expressly grant to it at the time it collects such data (which you may withdraw at any time after giving it, as described in this policy). This includes:

* Processing your personal data to send you marketing communications, in cases where you have consented to such use, including sending you email communications to market and sell the Services, including to co-market, co-promote and cross sell Learneo Services.
* Collecting your personal data through the use of advertising or tracking cookies based on your prior consent and use your personal data for showing you advertisements, including interest-based or online behavioral advertising.
* Collecting your personal data (including sensitive personal data) for identification verification purposes as described in this privacy policy.
* Learning how you use and interact with one or more of our Services for the purposes of improving the Services, including testing, research, internal analytics and product development (when such processing is performed with cookies or otherwise in a manner requiring consent).
* To measure our progress towards corporate goals and key performance indicators, including gathering commercial data related to our subscription Services (when such processing is performed with cookies or otherwise in a manner requiring consent).

When we process personal data based on your consent, it will be expressly indicated to you at the point and time of collection. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. We refer to the EEA and UK Resident Rights section below for further information.

* _Legal Obligation_: Learneo processes your personal data where necessary to fulfill its legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal processing (e.g. subpoenas or warrants). This includes for the purposes of:
    * Fraud protection, security and debugging.
    * Responding to data subject requests under applicable privacy laws.
    * Preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities.
    * Data retention and administration obligations.
    * Complying with requests of competent supervisory authorities and legal agencies.
* _Other Processing Grounds_: From time to time, Learneo may also need to process personal data if it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or others, or if it is necessary for a task carried out in the public interest.

#### EEA and UK Resident Rights

* _Access_: You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process personal data concerning you, and request access to and/or a copy of the personal data we hold about you.
* _Rectification_: If you believe that any personal data we hold about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You may correct some of this information directly by logging on to your account.
* _Erasure_: You can request that we erase some or all of your personal data from our systems. Under the GDPR and the UK GDPR, this right is subject to certain exceptions. Please see the Data Retention section on the purposes for which we retain limited personal data.
* _Withdrawal of Consent_: If we are processing your personal data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time with effect for future processing operations. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your personal data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Services.
* _Portability_: You can ask for your personal data in a machine-readable format. You can also request that we transmit the data to another controller where technically feasible.
* _Restriction of Processing_: You can ask us to restrict further processing of your personal data.

**_Objection:_ You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your personal data for certain purposes, such as for direct marketing purposes**

Please note that these rights can often be exercised only under specific conditions set out in the GDPR and UK GDPR as applicable. Furthermore , we may not be able to fully comply with your request in circumstances where doing so is manifestly unfounded or excessive, or if it is not permitted by law. In those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision. In some cases, we may also need you to provide us with additional information, which may include personal data, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request.

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please see the [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-contact-us) section of this policy.

#### Cross Border Transfers of Personal Data

Learneo has offices located in the United States, Israel, India, The Netherlands, Germany, and Canada and may continue to grow in other countries. We also have service providers both in the United States and throughout the world. As such, Learneo and our service providers may transfer your personal data to, or access it in, jurisdictions that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction. These transfers are necessary in order for us to provide our Services. When we transfer information about individuals based in the EEA or UK outside of those countries, we will take appropriate measures to safeguard the transfer as required by applicable law, including:

* **Adequacy Decisions**: European Commission decisions recognizing that certain countries and territories outside of the EEA ensure an adequate level of protection for personal data. Depending on your use of our Services, when we transfer your personal data from the EEA to Israel or the UK, we rely on the European Commission's adequacy decision for Israel and the UK. Further, where we transfer your personal data from the EEA to an US recipient participating in the DPF (including the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (DPF), where applicable), we rely on the European Commission's adequacy decision for the US.
* **Standard Contractual Clauses**: Transfers to countries that don't have an adequacy decision typically take place on the basis of the European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses (together with the UK Annex for transfers from the UK), which we use for transfers to countries including but not limited to the US (where the recipient does not participate in the DPF), and Singapore.

In certain circumstances, cross border transfers may take place on the basis of exemptions provided for under applicable data protection law.

You may always contact us to request a copy of the transfer measures that we have taken to safeguard the transfer of your personal data.

##### Complaints

You have the right to lodge a complaint about our practices with respect to your personal data before a supervisory data protection authority.

* If you are in Europe, an up-to-date list of data protection authorities is available at [https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members\_en](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en).
* If you are in the Netherlands, the data protection authority is the Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens, available at: [https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/).
* If you are in the UK, the data protection authority is the UK Information Commissioner's Office available at [https://ico.org.uk/](https://ico.org.uk/).

#### Additional Terms for Australian Residents

If you reside in Australia, the following additional terms apply in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles ("APPs") and the Privacy Act 1988 ("APA"). If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this policy, the following terms shall prevail.

##### _Government ID_

To the extent we collect any government ID (such as driver's license, photo card, etc), we recognise that government ID is a special category of personal information that is subject to a higher standard of privacy protection compared to other types of personal data. Notwithstanding any other part of this policy, to the extent that we collect any such government ID from you, we will only collect, use and disclose such data strictly for the identity verification purpose set out in this privacy policy or for a purpose permitted under APP 9. We will not handle your government ID in any other manner or for any other purpose. Subject to any retention requirements under law or otherwise specified in this privacy policy, we will destroy or de-identify any record of your government ID stored in our systems when we no longer need to use it.

##### _How To Access, Correct, Update, or Delete Your Personal Data_

You can request to access, correct, update or delete your personal data by contacting us using the contact details provided under the Contact us section in Part One.

You can request access to any personal data we hold about you at any time. However please be aware that from time to time we may need to reject your request to access personal data we hold about you, if we believe such rejection to be necessary and to the extent allowed by law.

If we do not provide you with access to any of your personal data, or do not correct any of your personal data, we will provide you with our reasons. If you are not satisfied with our reasons, you may make a complaint as set out below under the Complaints section.

##### _Complaints_

We take your privacy concerns seriously. If you have a complaint regarding our handling of your personal data or concerning our privacy practices, you may file a complaint with our Privacy Officer using the contact provided under the Contact us section in Part One. Our Compliance team will confirm receipt of your complaint and review it with our legal team. If we believe an investigation is necessary, we will open an investigation into your complaint. We may need to contact you to request further details of your complaint. If an investigation has been opened following a complaint made by you, we will contact you with the result of that complaint as soon as possible.

If you are not satisfied with the outcome of your complaint, you may refer your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner by contacting 1300 363 992 or by visiting the website www.oaic.gov.au. Further information about the APA and the APPs is also available from the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

##### _Transfers of Personal Data Outside Australia_

We may share your personal data amongst Learneo, with third party service-providers and other third parties that require such information to assist us in providing Services to you. Your personal data may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than Australia, including United States, Israel, India, The Netherlands, and Canada or other countries as might be the case in the future. We will only transfer your personal data overseas for the same purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Personal data that is stored overseas may not be subject to the APA or the APPs. However, we will not transfer or permit any of your personal data to be transferred outside of Australia unless we have taken reasonable steps to ensure the transfer is in compliance with applicable laws, and in any case to a recipient that has privacy protections in place which are at least substantially similar to which the APPs protect information.

##### _Consequences If We Can't Collect Your Personal Data_

If you do not provide us with the personal data we need, we may not be able to provide appropriate services, targeted content or relevant information to you, and in some cases you may not be able to use our Services.

#### Additional Terms for Mexican Residents

##### _Purposes and Consent_

For residents of Mexico, all of the purposes listed in this privacy policy are considered necessary for the existence, continuity and fulfilling of our contractual relationship with you and are considered primary purposes. Learneo therefore does not require your express consent for the processing of your data for these purposes. Any other purpose other than these primary purposes are considered secondary purposes, to which you will be provided notice and opportunity to object to processing of your personal data for those purposes at the time. You may also notify us of your objection by email to [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Please note that for processing described in the “Sharing with Third Parties” section, we will obtain your consent for such transfers when required by law. Otherwise, exceptions under Mexican law permit the processing described in this section, such as to perform our contract with you to provide our Services, to comply with applicable law or administration of justice. Sharing to “Service Providers” shall be considered a remission under Mexican law whereby each Service Provider is a data processor and bound by contractual terms restricting use of personal data processed on our behalf. Any “Business Transfers” described in that section are not a communication of data under Mexican law, they are considered an assignment of the data controller obligations to a third party, which shall be communicated to you through the availability of a new privacy policy.

##### _Your Rights under Mexican Privacy Law_

You are entitled to: (i) access to your personal data kept by Learneo (ii); be informed of the treatment given to your personal data by Learneo; (iii) request rectification of your personal data in case the information is incorrect or incomplete; (iv) request cancellation of your personal data; (v) refuse to the treatment of your personal data; and (vi) revoke your consent for the processing of your personal data (together "ARCO Rights").

You may exercise your ARCO rights by contacting Learneo compliance at [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with the subject "ARCO Rights", and providing the following information:

* Your name and address
* The specific Learneo Service you are using
* Supporting documentation of your domicile in Mexico,
* A clear and precise description of the personal data you are seeking to access or the privacy right you are exercising
* Any additional details relevant to your request.

We will review and respond to your request within the timeframe permitted by law.

PART TWO: PRODUCT SPECIFIC PRIVACY DETAILS
------------------------------------------

This Part Two describes the privacy practices specific to a Learneo business and one or more of its Services indicated in that section. Please click on the applicable link below for details.

**

##### Course Hero Services

**

See [Part One](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) for a list of Learneo Services that are included in this Course Hero Services section.

### Table of Contents

Personal Data We Collect
------------------------

### _Information You Provide_

#### When You Use Course Hero Services

The types of information we collect and process depend on the specific Course Hero Service you are using, the type of account you have, and how you use our Services.

* **Profile or Contact Data.** When you sign up with any of the Course Hero Services, we may collect your:
    * First and last name
    * Email address
    * Phone number
        * Collected for verifying your account and preventing fraud; required for Course Hero tutors;
        * We may also collect phone numbers to send you messages based on your express consent at the time of collection. For example, unless you voluntarily provided your phone number to enable SMS texting in your account settings, we will give you the option to provide it after submitting a question so that we can, with your consent, send you text updates on tutor response.
    * Mailing address
    * School
    * Graduation date (month & year)
    * Profile image
    * Courses
    * Major/area of study
    * Country of residence (tutor applicants)
    * Area of expertise (tutor applicants)
    * Highest level of education, and evidence of educational background such as a diploma, professional certificate/license, or school transcript (tutor applicants only)
    * Confirmation of age 16+ (Course Hero tutor applicants)
    * Additional "_Tutor Profile Data_" on Course Hero: Graduation date (month and year), a profile picture, the name of the school you attended, prior relevant experience, and other platforms tutored on.
    * Additional "_Educator Profile Data_" on Course Hero: Academic role and subject/department, resume (to parse out optional data on your Course Hero profile), a profile picture, a public profile link (such as a link to your faculty or LinkedIn profile), courses taught, your biography, education (school, degree, field of study, dates), teaching history, publications and awards.

* **Government Identifiers.** When you sign up to be a Tutor on Course Hero, we may collect your:
    * Government identification number or driver's license number (for identity verification only)
    * _Canadian residents only_: If you want to claim earnings as a tutor, we collect your tax information, which consists of your full name or business entity name, type of ID (SIN for an individual or program account number for a business), government ID number, and permanent address for the purpose of reporting earnings up to a certain amount

* **Payment Data.** When you sign up for a paid subscription or choose to utilize any of our paid services, we will collect your:
    * Payment card holder name
    * Billing city, state, postal code and country
    * Payment card type
    * First 6 and/or last 4 digits of payment card
    * Expiration date
    * A PayPal email specifically to receive payments from Course Hero

* **Commercial Data**
    * Purchase history

* **Online Identifiers.** When you create an account on Course Hero, we will collect:
    * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords that you use to manage your Course Hero account

* **Third-Party Login Data.** If you use a third-party service to sign-into your Course Hero account, we will collect your:
    * Email
    * Name and profile picture
    * User ID and education data (if applicable)

* **Professional or Employment-Related Data.** If you sign up to use Course Hero as an educator or tutor, we will also collect:
    * Educator resume information, job title, and job history
    * Educator school/faculty issued ID or other document that verifies your status as an educator
    * Educator school-issued email or personal email address\*
        * \*Note: If you provide a personal email but want to create an educator account, or if you are unable to be verified by our third party identification service provider as described in this policy, we will collect a copy of your school/faculty issued ID or other document that verifies your status as an educator, such as your employment offer, letter of acceptance, or copy of a pay stub. We require that you redact personal data (except your name and your employer) from these documents before they are shared with us).
    * Tutor education level
    * Tutor diploma/transcript

* **Non-Public Education Data.** Depending on how you use our Services, we may collect the following information from you directly:
    * Tutor grades or transcripts (Course Hero Tutors)
    * Scholarship applicant information (see the [When you Apply for Scholarships](#when-you-apply-for-scholarships) section below)

* **Sensitive Personal Data.** If you apply or use our services as a tutor, we will collect your:
    * Biometric data, solely for the purposes of tutor identification verification and to detect and prevent fraud on Course Hero, obtained with your express consent as further described in this policy and at the time of collection.

* **Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide.** Depending on how your use our Services or interact with us, we may collect:
    * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us.
    * Data in your hard drive or removable storage media, when you choose to upload Content to our Services.

#### When you Apply to be a Tutor on Course Hero

If you apply to be a tutor, using the information above we will verify your identity as part of your tutor application review. We may also verify your identity when you withdraw funds from your tutor account or to protect your account when we detect fraudulent activity. To verify your identity, we will collect your mobile phone number for SMS verification, an image of your photo ID (such as your driver's license or other government ID; excluding passport), as well as a photo of yourself. If your professional license is issued by a government, and/or you provide a government-issued professional license card, we will verify the authenticity of that information. We may use a third-party identification service provider to collect this personal data to perform this identity verification on our behalf. When we do, we will inform you about the service provider we use and the process for verifying your identity with them. Any of the identification service providers we use will only process your personal data at our instruction and for the purposes of verifying your identity on Course Hero. In those cases, we will only collect and use the personal data you provide for identification verification purposes with your consent that you provide at the time we collect this information. You can revoke this consent at any time by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We also collect your PayPal email in order to transfer your earnings for tutoring on Course Hero. For more details on Applying to be a Tutor with Course Hero, see our [Support Article](https://support.coursehero.com/hc/en-us/sections/4431386351255-Applying-to-be-a-Tutor)

#### When you Use our AI-Powered Search, Question Prompts, or Chat Features

When you use certain Course Hero Services features like the Course Hero AI-powered chat or search functionalities, we will collect your inputs to those features along with Profile or Contact Data and the Automatically Collected Information (described below) associated with your use of that feature. These features may allow you to input any text that you choose. We will never request that you provide your personal data in any of these input fields, and strongly advise against doing so. Please note that any data input into an AI-powered chat or search feature in Course Hero Services may be stored for up to 120 days, and otherwise in accordance with our business data retention and deletion policies. We will use this information for the purposes of providing and improving the relevant feature to you.

#### When You Communicate with Us

When you contact customer support, we will collect your first and last name, the email registered with your Course Hero Services account, and the last 4 digits of your credit card number (if you are using one of our paid services). You may also choose to provide us with additional information, such as name on credit card and phone number, or other account details relevant to your inquiry.

When you provide feedback, we collect your email and any other personal data you may provide us.

#### When You Participate in a Contest or Sweepstakes

When you choose to participate in one of our contests or sweepstakes, we collect your email, mailing address (for physical prizes), and school you attend. In some cases we may require your separate consent to participate and agreement to specific terms. If you are selected as the winner, we also collect a copy of your driver's license and student ID to confirm your identity and eligibility, after which the copies are deleted. For cash prizes, we require winners to complete a W-2 tax and direct deposit information used solely to make payment to you.

#### When You Apply for Scholarships

When you apply for a Course Hero scholarship, we collect your name, email address, phone number, as well as biographical, education, financial, and work history information.

#### When You Attend a Virtual or In-Person Course Hero Services Event

From time to time, Course Hero hosts in person and/or virtual events for educators and students, such as the annual_Course Hero Education Summit_. When you register to attend one of our events, we may collect your name, email, school, title, and country of residence.

#### When You Choose to Participate in Research to Improve our Services

We periodically conduct research to help improve our Services, including by sending you invitations for online surveys or questionnaires, or to participate in research interviews. In such cases, we may collect demographic data about you, such as gender, age, school major or topic of study, and education level, on a voluntary and anonymized basis. We may also ask you for information about your use of Course Hero related to our research. We may use a third-party research service provider to collect research information or administer online research on our behalf. Your participation in research to help improve our Services is voluntary and may be subject to a separate research participant consent form or other agreement. In the event that your participation in research involves the use of our Services for research purposes, this Privacy Policy will apply.

In some cases, research participants may be asked to submit sensory data, such as photos, videos or recordings of a participant's environment, which we only collect and use for research purposes when you choose to participate and with your consent.

### _Collected Through Your Use of Course Hero Services_

We automatically collect the following information whenever you use Course Hero Services:

* **Usage Information** (information on your activity and how you use Course Hero Services, such as the date and time of visits, page views, and interactions, non-identifiable request IDs, referring links to/from any page, and time spent in a session).
* **Inference Information** about your usage of Course Hero Services, such as whether you are a frequent user of a particular feature, a high-volume document uploader, or an advanced tutor in a particular topic based on your response history. We use this inference data to help provide you the best user experience on Course Hero Services.
* **Device and Connection Information** (such as your internet protocol (IP) address, domain server, ISP or wireless carrier, device ID, device type, operating system, and web browser type).
* **General Location information** (approximated location based on your IP address), to show you relevant content, identify the applicable regional subscription offering to you, to detect/identify fraud on our Services, and for other commercially reasonable business purposes.

### _Information from Third-Party Sources_

#### When You Use Course Hero Services with Third Party Services

If you choose to sign up with the Course Hero Services using a third-party log-in service, you will provide us or allow the log-in service to provide us with your personal data as specified by that third-party log-in service. For example, if you choose to sign up using Facebook, you will provide us or allow Facebook to provide us with your personal data, such as your name, email, user ID, profile picture, and education data (school, school type, school name, graduation year), if available. If you use Google, you will provide us or allow Google to provide us with your name, email, and profile picture, if available. If you use Apple, you will have the option to allow Apple to provide us with your email address.

For more information about the personal data shared with Course Hero, please see the third-party log-in services' (Facebook, Google and Apple's) privacy policies.

Certain functionalities on the Services may permit interactions that you initiate between the Services and certain third-party services, such as third-party social networks (“Social Features”). Examples of Social Features include enabling you to send content such as contacts and photos between the Services and third-party services; “liking” or “sharing” Course Hero Services content, and to otherwise connect the Services to a Third-Party Services (e.g., to pull or push information to or from the Services). If you use Social Features, information you post or provide access to may be publicly displayed on the Services (see “Information You Disclose Publicly or to Others” section above) or by the third-party services that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a third-party service that references the Services (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with a Course Hero Service in a tweet or status update), your post may be used on or in connection with the Services or otherwise by Learneo.

#### Publicly Accessible Information on the Course Hero Services

Depending on how you use our Services, the following data may be publicly accessible on the Course Hero Services:

* If you have a **student account**, your username and school, as well as graduation date and profile picture, if provided.
* If you have a **tutor account**, your username, information about your active status on Course Hero, and any Tutor Profile Data. If you upload photos, videos or recordings of your environment to answer a student question, the attachment(s) (together with your answer) will also be publicly accessible.
* If you have an **educator account**, your first and last name, school where you teach, and any Educator Profile Data.
* If anyone uploads Content on the Course Hero Services, any personal data included in your Submission. Any Content you upload will be considered “public” and accessible by anyone including Learneo. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, unless otherwise explicitly agreed by us, personal information included in your Submission is not subject to our usage or sharing disclosure limitations, or other obligations, and may be used and shared or disclosed by Learneo and third parties to the fullest extent not prohibited by applicable law. Please do not include personal data in your Submission that you would not want to be publicly available.

#### Information from Creative Commons or Publicly Available on Third-Party Sites

We may collect the first and last name of any professor, educator, or instructor whose name is publicly listed in connection with a course on a publicly-accessible website for the purposes of establishing correct course information on Course Hero.

We may collect the first and last name of any author's work available in the Creative Commons for the purposes of establishing correct authorship attribution or creating author profiles.

Our Uses
--------

We use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the [Our Purposes: How We Use Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One of this policy.

For UK and EEA residents, please see the Additional Terms for European Economic Area and UK Residents in Part One for our lawful basis for processing your personal data.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

Below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months.

| Category of Personal Data | Personal Data We Collect | Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data: |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Profile or Contact Data | * First and last name<br>* Email<br>* Phone number<br>* Mailing address<br>* School<br>* Graduation date<br>* Profile image<br>* Courses | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers<br>* \*Payment Processors<br><br>\*Our third party payment processors are **Google Pay, Apple Pay, PayPal, Braintree, Stripe and Recurly.** If you sign up as a paying subscriber, your payment information (such as your bank or credit card number) is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see each payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors collect your payment information necessary to process your payment, and share limited payment information with Course Hero as described in the [Payment Data](#payment-data) row below. |
| Identifiers | * SIN or program account number (Canadians claiming earnings only)<br>* Government identification number or driver's license number(identity verification only) | * Service Providers |
| Payment Data | * Card holder name<br>* Billing city, state, postal code and country<br>* Payment card type<br>* First 6 and last 4 digits of payment card<br>* Expiration date | * Service Providers<br>* Payment Processors<br>* Analytics Providers (only first 6 digits of card) |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history | * Service Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Device/IP Data | * IP address<br>* Device ID<br>* Type of device/operating system/browser used to access the Services<br>* Session IDs and group session IDs (together using cookies) | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Browsing or search history<br>* Web page interactions<br>* Referring webpage/source through which you accessed the Services<br>* Statistics associated with the interaction between device or browser and the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Data | * Email<br>* Name and profile picture<br>* user ID and education data | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| Professional or Employment-Related Data | * Educator resume<br>* Educator job title<br>* Educator job history<br>* Tutor education level<br>* Tutor diploma/transcript | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Non-Public Education Data | * Tutor grades or transcripts<br>* Scholarship applicant - student financial information | * Service Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers<br>* Payment Processors |
| Sensory Data | * Photos, videos or recordings of a user's environment (research participants; questions and answers on tutoring service) | * Service Providers |
| Sensitive Personal Data | * Biometric data (Course Hero tutor applicants only) | * Identification Service Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |

Additional Data Security
------------------------

In addition to the security measures identified in the [Data Security](#part-one-data-security) section in Part One, the information security controls implemented by Course Hero are audited annually by an external third-party certified Qualified Security Assessor for compliance with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) security standards.

We also implement Google’s Invisible reCAPTCHA technology on our Services in order to reduce spam and prevent abuse of our Services. Your use of the Invisible reCAPTCHA is subject to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).

Data Retention
--------------

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, when you use a Course Hero Service, we retain your personal information for as long as that Course Hero Services account remains open with us, and for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. In the event that you choose to register for multiple Course Hero Services using the same email address, we may link your accounts (as stated on the applicable sign-up page), and if we do, we will retain all of your personal data in a single Course Hero Services profile associated with that email, and for the same duration. In some cases, we retain personal information for longer and for other legitimate purposes, including if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, enforcing and preventing violations of our Terms, to fight spam, protecting or defending our rights, property and users, to resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form, where that information would not identify you personally. Applicable storage periods are determined on a case-by-case basis. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable legal requirements, the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes we process your personal information for, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means. We will maintain certain types of personal information for a limited duration. For example, we keep account information like your account email address for as long as your account is in existence, because we need it to operate your account.

In addition to the above, as stated in the [When You Use Our AI-Powered Search, Question Prompts, or Chat Features section](#when-you-use-our-ai-powered-search) above, any data input into an AI-powered chat or search feature in Course Hero Services may be stored for up to 120 days, and otherwise in accordance with our business data retention and deletion policies. We will use this information for the purposes of providing and improving the relevant feature to you.

Deleting Your Account
---------------------

If you would like to delete your account, you can do this directly by going to "My Account" in your Account Settings for the relevant Course Hero Service. If you choose to delete your account: 1) your account information (username and any other information you provided on your account) will be deleted from the applicable Course Hero Service, but your Submissions may remain in accordance with the applicable Service Terms ; 2) we will not be able to provide you with Services, and you will no longer receive emails from us; and 3) you will not be able to use the email associated with your account on that Service again. Please note that if you registered for more than one Course Hero Service using the same account, if you delete one of your Course Hero Services accounts all of your accounts will also be deleted in accordance with this privacy policy.

If the GDPR, UK GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other applicable privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from our Services and you want to exercise that right, please see [Contact Information for Specific Learneo Services](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) in Part One for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

* Bartleby Cookie Policy
* For all other Student Brands websites, please refer to that specific Service for a link to the applicable Cookie Policy.

**

##### LitCharts

**

### Table of Contents

Personal Data Collected
-----------------------

### _When you sign up with LitCharts_

When you create an account on LitCharts, we collect your email, country of residence, date of birth, username, and user-type (student, teacher/educator, parent, librarian, general interest reader).

If you sign up for a paid subscription on LitCharts, payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors are **Stripe and PayPal (on the LitCharts Service)** . For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see the payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us.

### _Collected through your use of our Services_

When you use our Services, we collect the following information:

* Usage information (such as the date and time of visits, pages viewed, links to/from any page, and time spent in a session)
* Device information (such as your internet protocol (IP) address, Internet service provider, operating system, and web browser type)
* Location information (based on your IP address), to detect/identify fraud on our Services

### _Collected about you from third party sources_

If you choose to create an account with us using a third party log-in service (such as Facebook or Google), you will provide us or allow the log-in service to provide us with your personal data, such as your email, name and/or username, if available, and any other personal data specified by that third-party log-in services. For more information about the personal data shared with LitCharts, please see the third-party log-in services (Facebook or Google) privacy policies.

In some cases, we may receive personal data about you from a third party, such as your employer or academic institution, to enable your account setup to use our Services.

### _Provided by you when you communicate with us_

When you contact customer support, we collect your first and last name, email, and any other personal data you may provide to us when you complete our customer support form.

We also collect your email and any other personal data you may provide to us when you choose to respond to surveys or questionnaires we send for research purposes or as part of our Services, or when you provide feedback.

### _When you Use our AI-Powered Features_

When you use our AI-powered tools, such as our AI-assisted search or Q&A tools like “Ask LitCharts AI”, we will collect your inputs to those features, along with your account information and the data in the “Collected through your use of our Services” section associated with your use of that feature. These features may allow you to input any text that you choose. We will never request that you provide your personal data in any of these input fields, and strongly advise against doing so. Please note that any data input into an AI-powered feature in LitCharts will be stored in accordance with our business data retention and deletion policies. We will use your inputs for the purposes of providing and improving the relevant feature.

Our Uses
--------

We use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the [How We Use Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One of this policy.

For UK and EEA residents, please see [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) in Part One of this policy for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes we describe.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

In addition to the [How We Share Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-share-your-personal-data) section in Part One, when you use LitCharts, below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of Personal Data** | **Personal Data We Collect** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data:** |
| Profile or Contact Data | * Email<br>* Country<br>* Date of birth<br>* Username (LitCharts Service only)<br>* User type (e.g., teacher, student, general interests, reader, librarian, and or parent) (LitCharts Service only) | * Service Providers<br>* Payment Processors |
| Payment Data | * Card holder name<br>* Billing address<br>* Payment card type<br>* Last 4 digits of payment card<br>* Expiration date | * Service Providers |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history<br>* Consumer profiles | * Service Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Service Providers |
| Device/IP Data | * IP address<br>* Type of device/operating system/browser used to access the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Web page interact<br>    <br>* Non-identifiable request IDs | * Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Service Data (LitCharts Service only) | * Email | * Service Providers |
| Demographic Data | * Age/date of birth<br>* Postal code | * Service Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information | * Service Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us | * Service Providers |

Data Retention
--------------

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, we retain personal information about you for as long as you have an open account with us, as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. In some cases, we retain personal information for longer and for other legitimate purposes, including if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, enforcing and preventing violations of our Terms, to fight spam, protecting or defending our rights, property and users, to resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form, where that information would not identify you personally. Applicable storage periods are determined on a case-by-case basis. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable legal requirements, the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes we process your personal information for, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means. We will maintain certain types of personal information for a limited duration. For example, we keep account information, like your name, email address, and password, for as long as your account is in existence because we need it to operate your account.

Deleting Your Account
---------------------

You can delete the personal data LitCharts holds about you directly within your user account, under "Account Settings".

If the GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from our Services and you want to exercise that right, please read [Part One](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

To view the LitCharts Cookie Policy, [click here](https://www.litcharts.com/cookies).

**

##### Symbolab

**

### Table of Contents

Personal Data Collected
-----------------------

### _When you sign up with Symbolab_

When you create an account on Symbolab, we collect your first and last name and email. If you sign up to be a paying subscriber, we collect your billing email. Payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors are **Google Pay, Apple Pay, PayPal and Stripe**. For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see the payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us.

### _Collected through your use of our Services_

When you use our Services, we collect location information (based on your IP address), to identify the applicable default language and regional subscription offering on our Services.

### _Collected about you from third party sources_

If you choose to create an account with us using a third-party log-in service (such as Facebook, Office365 or Google), you will provide us or allow the third-party social network or log-in service to provide us with your personal data, such as your email and username, if available, and any other personal data specified by that third-party log-in service.

For more information about the personal data shared with Symbolab, please see the third-party log-in services (Facebook, Office365 or Google) privacy policies.

### _Provided by you when you communicate with us_

When you contact us to provide feedback, you have the option to provide us with your name, email, and any other personal data.

When you contact us for customer support, we collect your email, device information (operating system and web browser type), and any other personal data you may choose to provide us.

When you respond to surveys or questionnaires we send for research purposes or as part of our Services, we collect your email and any other personal data you may choose to provide us.

Our Uses
--------

We use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the [How We Use Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One of this policy.

For UK and EEA residents, please see [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) in Part One of this policy for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes we describe.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

In addition to the [How We Share Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-share-your-personal-data) section in Part One, when you use Symbolab below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of Personal Data** | **Personal Data We Collect** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data:** |
| Profile or Contact Data | * First and last name<br>* Email | * Service Providers |
| Payment Data | * Billing email<br>* Card holder name<br>* Billing address<br>* Payment card type<br>* Last 4 digits of payment card<br>* Expiration date | * Service Providers<br>* Payment Processors |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history | * Service Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Service Providers |
| Device/IP Data | * Type of device/operating system/browser for support | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Browsing or search history<br>* Web page interactions<br>* Referring webpage/source through which users accessed the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Service Data | * Email<br>* Username on social network or third-party login service | * Service Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us | * Service Providers |

Data Retention
--------------

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, we retain personal information about you for as long as you have an open account with us, as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. In some cases, we retain personal information for longer and for other legitimate purposes, including if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, enforcing and preventing violations of our Terms, to fight spam, protecting or defending our rights, property and users, to resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form, where that information would not identify you personally. Applicable storage periods are determined on a case-by-case basis. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable legal requirements, the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes we process your personal information for, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means. We will maintain certain types of personal information for a limited duration. For example, we keep account information, like your name, email address, and password, for as long as your account is in existence because we need it to operate your account.

Deleting Your Account
---------------------

You can delete the personal data Symbolab holds about you directly within your user account, under "Account Management".

If the GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from Symbolab and you want to exercise that right, please read [Part One](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

To view our Cookie Policy, [click here](https://www.symbolab.com/cookie-policy).

**

##### QuillBot

**

### Table of Contents

Personal Data Collected
-----------------------

### _When you sign up with QuillBot_

When you register for an account to use our Services, we ask you for your **name** and **email**. We may also ask for other information about you to help customize your experience, such as your writing style or purpose for using QuillBot, your preferred language or your education level. If you sign up for our premium Services, payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors are **Amazon Pay, Stripe, PayPal, Chargebee, Razorpay, Google Pay and Apple Pay**. For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see the payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us. Our payment processors may share limited payment data with us, including card type, last 4 digits of card, token number, expiration date, and country or PayPal email subject to restrictions in the applicable law in your jurisdiction.

### _Collected through your use of QuillBot_

When you use our Services, we collect the following information:

* Usage information (such as the date and time of visits, pages viewed, links to/from any page, and time spent in a session)
* Device information (such as your internet protocol (IP) address, Internet service provider, operating system, computer model, language settings and CPU details, and web browser type)
* Inference Information about your usage of QuillBot, such as whether you are a frequent document uploader or user of a particular feature. We also make inferences about the text you input in order to provide you a better experience, for example by categorizing your text inputs to suggest the best QuillBot feature for your uses.
* Location information (approximated, based on your IP address).

We may also collect personal data you provide or otherwise make available to us when you use different features in our Services. For example:

* We collect your text inputs or other information you provide in any of our Services, including any personal data contained within.
* When you use the Plagiarism Checker, we store a copy of your document, which includes any information contained within.
* When you use our Paraphraser tool, we will collect any information you paraphrase, including personal data you enter into Paraphraser.
* When you upload documents to our Services, we will store both a copy of the original document (or the text of the original document) as well as any outputs we provide (like the paraphrased version) and any information contained within those outputs.
* When you use QuillBot Flow, we will collect any information, including personal data, you enter into your project(s) within the editor.

When you use the voice recognition feature on QuillBot Flow for audio to text conversion, the audio to text conversion occurs in real time and audio is not stored by us; however, the text converted from audio input that is added by you to your project(s) is stored by us in accordance with this policy.

### _Collected when you use QuillBot's Browser Extensions_

When you use QuillBot's browser extensions, the contents in the email you prepare and receive, chat messages you write (excluding history or chats received), documents you create, search queries, and text you input on multiline fields on websites you visit ("Your Content"), as transmitted by you in connection with your use of our extension, will be used in real time on our machine learning algorithm to generate outputs, after which Your Content is deleted from our Services. We only store Your Content after you provide your consent, which you can revoke at any time within the extension icon found on the right top corner of your browser.

When you use QuillBot's Chrome extension, we will store your Command Data, which includes the text and metadata (including any personal data as described in this Privacy Policy) of any command that you provide to QuillBot to perform a specific function. For example, when you provide the command "Write an email for a business proposal," we will store that text and the metadata associated with it, including your personal data like your QuillBot account and browser information. We use the Command Data we store to understand usage, optimize our Services, and provide the best experience on QuillBot.

Command Data is distinct from Your Content, which includes the contents of the email you prepare and receive, chat messages you write (excluding history or chats received), documents you create, search queries, and text you enter in multiline fields on websites you visit. We process Command Data in real time using our machine learning algorithm to generate outputs. After this real-time processing, Your Content is deleted from our Services.

We also collect URLs and usage information (in addition to the usage information described above), such as the number of times you disable/enable the extension on a website. This information helps us understand how you use this service and how we can improve it.

We do not access your contacts, text in single-line fields (which are more likely to contain personal data), or content in fields marked "sensitive," such as credit card, password, email address, or email subject fields.

We only collect Your Content when the QuillBot icon is displayed and enabled, indicating that Your Content will be grammar-checked or paraphrased. We only store Your Content with your consent. You can disable the extension or revoke consent at any time by clicking the QuillBot icon in the top-right corner of your browser and going to "Preferences."

We also collect URLs and usage information when you use QuillBot on a website (in addition to the usage information described immediately above), such as the number of times you disable/enable the extension on a website, which we retain to help us understand how you use this Service and to help us improve it. We only collect Your Content when the QuillBot icon is displayed and enabled, indicating that Your Content will be grammar checked or paraphrased. You can choose to disable the QuillBot extension at any time on the top right corner of your browser. We do not access your contacts, text in single-line input fields (which are more likely to contain personal data), or content in fields marked "sensitive" such as credit card, password, email address or email subject fields.

### _Collected when you use the QuillBot Desktop App_

When you install the QuillBot desktop app, QuillBot will request permission to access your computer's accessibility features. This allows us to collect your inputs from within certain applications on your computer to enable us to provide our Services to you. Your inputs will be used in real time on our machine learning algorithm to generate outputs, after which they are deleted. Access to your accessibility features also allow us to identify apps you use but which are yet to be supported, so we can display a feedback widget. After you grant permissions to your computer's accessibility settings, you can choose when to use the QuillBot desktop app to help improve your writing at any time, by clicking on the QuillBot icon that appears when you open certain compatible apps on your computer.

### _Collected about you when you participate in QuillBot University_

If you choose to sign up for a QuillBot University event (including live webinars), we will collect your first and last name, email address, occupation, country of residence, and any other personal data you provide to us. We may use this personal data in order to process your registration, provide you with the event, and to improve our future events and our services.

### _Collected about you from third party sources_

If you choose to sign up with QuillBot using certain third-party log-in services (such as Facebook or Google) you will provide us or allow the log-in service to provide us with your personal data, such as your email, name and/or username, if available, and any other personal data specified by that third-party log-in service. For more information about the personal data shared with QuillBot, please see the third-party log-in service's (Facebook or Google) privacy policies.

In some cases, we may receive information about your interactions with products and services offered by our affiliates for which we provide technical or other services. We may also collect personal data about you from a third party, such as your employer or academic institution, to enable your account setup to use our Services. We will also receive limited payment information from our payment service providers (as described above), which we need to manage your QuillBot subscription.

We may collect the first and last name of any author's work available in the Creative Commons for the purposes of establishing correct authorship attribution and creating author profiles on QuillBot.

We use analytics services such as Google Analytics and Amplitude to collect and process certain analytics data when you use our Services. These services may also collect information about your use of other websites, apps, and online resources. For more information about our use of these services, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://quillbot.com/cookie-policy) . In addition, you can learn about Google's practices by going to [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) .

### _Provided by you when you communicate with us_

When you contact us for more information about QuillBot or for customer support, we collect your name, email, and the contents of your message to us.

If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will collect your email. When we send you emails, we may track whether you open them to learn how to deliver a better customer experience and improve our Services.

We collect your email and any other personal data you may provide to us when you choose to respond to surveys or questionnaires we send for research purposes or as part of our Services; or when you choose to provide feedback.

If you choose to connect to QuillBot using your Google account, you may also use the Upload from Drive feature on QuillBot Flow to connect your Google Drive account to QuillBot. You may then select which of your Google Drive files you wish to import, and use our Services to edit your document(s). You may only use the Upload from Drive feature after you grant QuillBot permission to "see and download" all of the files in your Google Drive account. QuillBot will collect and store the information contained in any Google Drive document you import as described in this policy. Quillbot's use and transfer to any other app of information received from Google APIs will adhere to the [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy) , including the Limited Use requirements.

### _Collected when you sign up for a Team Plan_

When you sign up for QuillBot's premium Services under a Team Plan, we collect personal data from Team Plan Owners, Administrators, and Writers (as defined in our Terms of Service) necessary to administer and operate the Services.

If you are a Team Plan Owner, we collect your first and last name and email address. You also have the option to provide us with your phone number, company name, Business Tax Identifier, and address. As Team Plan Owner, you may invite other individuals to join the Team Plan as either an Administrator or Writer. In such a case, we use your name on the email invitation to Writers and Administrators added by you. Payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us.

If you are a Writer or Administrator, we collect your email address from the Team Plan Owner to send you an invitation to join the Team Plan. To join a Team Plan, you will need to register an account with QuillBot. When you register an account, we will collect additional personal data as described in the "Collected When you sign up with QuillBot" section of this policy.

Our Uses
--------

When you use QuillBot, we use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the [How We Use Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One of this policy.

When you use QuillBot’s premium services under a Team Plan, we will not use your text inputs for the purposes of training our language models. This is a default setting for all QuillBot Team Plan users that does not require an opt-out or any action by the Team Plan Owner or user. We will still use and store your inputs to enhance and personalize your individual QuillBot experience, as described in this policy.

For UK and EEA residents, please see [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) in Part One of this policy for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes we describe.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

In addition to the How We Share Your Personal Data section in Part One, when you use QuillBot below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of Personal Data** | **Personal Data We Collect** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data:** |
| Profile or Contact Data | * First and last name<br>* Email | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers<br>* Payment Processors |
| Payment Data | * Billing address<br>* Payment card type<br>* Last 4 digits of payment card<br>* Expiration date | * Service Providers<br>* Payment Processors |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Service Providers |
| Device/IP Data | * IP address<br>* Device ID<br>* Type of device/operating system/browser used to access the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Browsing or search history<br>* Web page interactions<br>* Referring webpage/source through which you accessed the Services<br>* Statistics associated with the interaction between device or browser and the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Service Data | * Email<br>* Username on the social network | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us | * Service Providers |

Data Retention
--------------

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, we retain personal information about you for as long as you have an open account with us, as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. In some cases, we retain personal information for longer and for other legitimate purposes, including if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, enforcing and preventing violations of our Terms, to fight spam, protecting or defending our rights, property and users, to resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form, where that information would not identify you personally. Applicable storage periods are determined on a case-by-case basis. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable legal requirements, the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes we process your personal information for, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means. We will maintain certain types of personal information for a limited duration. For example, we keep account information like your account email address for as long as your account is in existence, because we need it to operate your account.

Deleting Your QuillBot Account
------------------------------

If you would like to delete the personal data QuillBot holds about you, you can request this via the [Contact Us](https://quillbot.com/contact) page or by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://languagetool.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

If the GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from QuillBot and you want to exercise that right, please read [Part One](#part-one-learneo-privacy-practices) for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

To view our Cookie Policy, [click here](https://quillbot.com/cookie-policy) .

**

##### Scribbr

**

### Table of Contents

Personal Data Collected
-----------------------

### _When you sign up with Scribbr_

When you sign up to use our Services, we collect:

* Your name, email and telephone number
* The user type: student, teacher or other user
* Level of education
* In which country you study
* At which school you study
* The field and year of study
* The expected graduation date

You will have the option to provide us with a billing name, email, and address, if different from the name and email used to create an account with us.

### _Collected through your use of Scribbr_

When you use our Services, we collect:

* IP address to, among other things, identify the applicable tax for services rendered
* Browsing history
* Usage information, and movements on our websites or websites of third parties gathered through tracking cookies. For detailed information about our use of cookies, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.scribbr.com/legal/cookie-policy/).

We collect any identifying information in the content of the document(s) you share with us. Specifically for proofreading services, when you use our Services, we use any identifying information we collect to help provide Services to you.

Payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors are **Adyen, PayPal, Apple Pay, and Google Pay**. For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see the payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us.

When you use Scribbr browser extensions, we collect certain information about the content of websites visited, such as the title, author(s) name, contributor(s) name, publication dates, and the name of the website. This information is used by us in real time to generate a citation. Depending on the website you visit when using our extension, this may include your personal information as author, including your full name. We also collect certain device and browser information as well as information about your usage, such as button clicks or mouse position, which we retain to help us improve the Service. You can choose to disable the Scribbr extension at any time on the top right corner of your browser.

When you use the Services to upload a PDF and generate a citation, we will collect and use all information contained in that document in order to generate the citation, including the author's personal information. This is necessary for us to generate the citation you request. We store the data from the PDFs you upload for this purpose for 30 days in order to operate and improve the Services.

The Services may contain links or connections to third party websites or services that are not owned or controlled by us (“Third Party Services”). We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, accuracy, terms and conditions, privacy policies, or practices of or opinions expressed by any Third Party Service that you interact with through the Services. When you access or use a Third Party Service via Scribbr, you may be subject to the privacy policy of such Third Party Service. The Third Party Services include:

* YouTube API, Google's Privacy Policy ([http://www.google.com/policies/privacy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy)).
* Google Books API, Books Privacy Policy [https://books.google.com/googlebooks/privacy.html](https://books.google.com/googlebooks/privacy.html), see also Help Center article at [https://support.google.com/books/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=100088](https://support.google.com/books/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=100088).
* Google Drive API, Google's Privacy Policy [(Privacy Policy - Privacy & Terms - Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

Scribbr's use and transfer to any other app of information received from Google APIs will adhere to the [Google API Services User Data Policy,](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy) including the Limited Use requirements.

### _Collected about you from third party sources_

If you choose to sign up with Scribbr using a third-party log-in service, you will provide us or allow the log-in service to provide us with your personal data as specified by that third-party log-in service. For example, if you choose to sign up using Facebook, you will provide us or allow Facebook to provide us with your personal data, such as your name, email, and ID assigned to your account, if available. If you use Google, you will provide us or allow Google to provide us with your name, email, ID assigned to your account, and profile picture, if available.

For more information about the personal data shared with us, please see the third-party log-in services (Facebook and Google's) privacy policies.

### _Provided by you when you communicate with us_

When you contact customer support, we collect:

* IP address
    
* Your name, email and telephone number
    
* Content of your message
    
* Details with regard to any follow-up

We collect your email and any other personal data you may provide to us when you respond to surveys or questionnaires we send for research purposes or as part of our Services, or when you provide feedback.

Our Uses
--------

We use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the [How We Use Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One of this policy.

For UK and EEA residents, please see [Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents](#part-one-additional-terms-for-european-economic-area-and-uk-residents) in Part One of this policy for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes we describe.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

In addition to the How We Share Your Personal Data section in Part One, when you use Scribbr below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of PersonalData** | **Examples of Personal Data We Collect** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data:** |
| Profile or Contact Data | * First and last name<br>* Email<br>* Phone number<br>* User type: student, teacher or other user<br>* Billing name, email, and address<br>* Level of education<br>* In which country you study<br>* At which school you study<br>* The field and year of study<br>* The expected graduation date | * Service Providers |
| Payment Data | * Card holder name<br>* Payment card type<br>* First 6 and last 4 digits of payment card | * Service Providers |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history<br>* Consumer profiles | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Parties Users Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| Device/IP Data | * IP address<br>* Device ID<br>* Domain server<br>* Type of device/operating system/browser used to access the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Browsing or search history<br>* Web page interactions<br>* Referring webpage/source through which you accessed the Services<br>* Non-identifiable request IDs<br>* Statistics associated with the interaction between device or browser and the Services | * Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Data | * Email<br>* Name and profile picture | * Service Providers |
| Consumer Demographic Data | * Postal code<br>* Education level | * Service Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information | * Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us<br>* Identifying information in the content of the document(s) you share with us<br>* Specifically for proofreading services: any identifying information you share with us to help provide services to you | * Service Providers |

Provided below are the locations of third party recipients with whom we share your personal data with:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Activity** | **Recipients** | **Location** |
| Visiting our website | Data processors engaged by us, such as advertising companies and hosting providers. | USA, The Netherlands, Germany, Ireland, Belgium |
| Using our Services | Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers and providers of plagiarism software. | USA, The Netherlands, Ireland |
| Customer service or otherwise corresponding with you | Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers and providers of CRM software. | USA, The Netherlands, Ireland, Germany |
| Other general purposes | Subcontractors or service providers such as auditing companies, consulting and law firms, and insurance companies; Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers; Relevant authorities | USA, The Netherlands, Ireland, Germany |

**Additional Scribbr Data Security**
------------------------------------

In addition to the security measures identified in the [Data Security](#part-one-data-security) section of this policy, we take the following security measures to protect your personal data:

* all documents are uploaded to Scribbr via a secure connection;
* logical and physical security (e.g. safe, doorman, firewall, network segmentation);
* technical control of the authorizations (as limited as possible) and keeping log files;
* management of the technical vulnerabilities (patch management);
* keeping software up-to-date (e.g. browsers, virus scanners and operating systems);
* making back-ups to safeguard availability and accessibility of the personal data;
* automatic erasure of outdated personal data;

Examples of organizational security measures taken by us are:

* special guidelines to which all employees and experts must abide, including confidentiality;
* uploaded documents are never shared with third parties, nor are they published;
* experts are obliged to delete your documents after having edited it;
    * assign responsibilities for information security;
    * promote privacy and security awareness among new and existing employees;
    * establish procedures to test, assess and evaluate security measures periodically;
        * check log files regularly;
* using a protocol for handling data breaches and other security incidents;
* conclude confidentiality, data processing and data protection agreements;
* assess whether the same objectives can be achieved with less personal data;
* provide access to personal data to as few people within the organization as possible; and
* define the decision-making and underlying considerations per processing.

We have internal security policies in place in which it is further described how we ensure an appropriate level of technical and organizational security measures. We also have a data breach policy in place in which it is described how we deal with a (possible) data breach.

Additional Information On Scribbr Data Retention
------------------------------------------------

Supplementing Part One of this policy, we do not store your personal data any longer than is strictly necessary for the purposes for which we process your personal data. We have put in place the following Retention Policy to ensure that your personal data are deleted after a reasonable period:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Activity** | **Retention period** |
| Visiting our website | Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.scribbr.com/legal/cookie-policy/) |
| Using our Services | * Your account: 3 years after your last activity on your account<br>* Edited documents: 12 months after editing<br>* Plagiarism checked and Grammar checked documents:<br>    * Document as a whole: 1 month after the check<br>    * Results of the check: 12 months after the check<br>* Citation Checker and Self Plagiarism Checker:<br>    * Quick checks: 60 minutes after the check<br>    * Regular checks: 90 days after the check |
| Customer service or otherwise corresponding with you | * If you have an account: up until the deletion of your account<br>* If you do not have an account: 9 months after the last date of contact |
| Job openings | 1 month or, upon your request, 3 months after you have applied |
| Other general purposes | Retention terms depend on the relevant purpose. In any case, no longer than necessary |

You can always delete your documents and results before the standardized retention terms manually via your account. Documents uploaded in the Citation Checker / Self-Plagiarism Checker can be deleted by contacting us. Please find our contact details in the [contact information above](#part-one-contact-us) .

Deleting Your Scribbr Account
-----------------------------

If you would like to delete your account from the Scribbr platform, you can do this directly by going to "Account" in "Settings." If you choose to delete your account: 1) your account information (first and last name, email address, phone number, user type, and any other information you provided on your account) will be deleted from the Scribbr platform, 2) all your uploaded documents and order details will be deleted automatically; this is irrevocable, and you can never use or enter this account again; 3) the Scribbr team will no longer have access to your documents. This means we cannot deal with possible complaints, as we cannot address complaints from deleted accounts.

If the GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from Scribbr and you want to exercise that right, please read Part One of this policy for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

To view our Cookie Policy, [click here](https://www.scribbr.com/legal/cookie-policy/) .

**

##### LanguageTool

**

### Table of Contents

Personal Data Collected
-----------------------

### _When you sign up with LanguageTool_

When you sign up to use our Services, we collect:

* Your first and last name
* Your email address
* Your billing address (optional when you purchase a Premium subscription)
* The country location where you sign up (approximated based on your IP address)
* Your language preference (as configured in your browser or device)
* The date and time of your registration

If you sign up for our premium Services, payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors. Our payment processors are **PayPal, Recurly, Stripe, GoCardless, and FastSpring (for Team Plans)**. For information on our payment processor's collection, use and storage of your personal data, please see the relevant payment processor's privacy policy. Our payment processors do not share your full payment card information with us. Our payment processors may share limited payment data with us, including card type, last 4 digits of card, token number, expiration date, and country or PayPal email subject to restrictions in the applicable law in your jurisdiction.

### _Collected Through Your Use of LanguageTool Services_

When you use any of our Services, we collect the following information:

* Usage information (such as the date and time of visits, pages viewed, links to/from any page, and time spent in a session)
* Device information (such as your internet protocol (IP) address, Internet service provider, operating system, computer model, language settings and CPU details, referrer URL, time zone information, data volume transferred, access status/ HTTP status code, and web browser type)
* Inference Information about your usage of LanguageTool, such as whether you are a frequent document uploader or user of a particular feature.
* Location information (approximated, based on your IP address).

### _Collected When You Use LanguageTool Apps and Extensions_

When you use our Apps and Extensions, we collect the following information:

* Date and time of your usage
* Length of the text
* Language of the input text (but not the text itself)
* Duration of processing
* Number and type of errors detected, the page from which the request was sent (e.g. languagetool.org)
* App or extension version number
* Date of installation
* A randomly generated ID assigned to the input text
* In the event you uninstall, we also collect the number of times the add-on was used and the URL of the page where the add-on was last used.
* An anonymously generated internal ID for error rules whenever you accept or ignore correction suggestions. When you ignore a suggestion, we also store the text fragment underlined as incorrect and 15 characters to the right and left of it to track and avoid future errors in our system.
* In the rare circumstance that you experience an internal software error, we may store an anonymized record of the error for up to 14 days so that we can identify and fix the issue.
* To improve the speed of our software, we store checked records and the errors found in them for up to 15 minutes on our servers in the main memory (not on a permanent storage medium). The storage is done without IP address or other information that would allow the records to be assigned to a person.
* Only if you have an account on languagetool.org and if you are logged into the add-on with that account: Our extension contacts our servers periodically (about once a day) to let us know that you are an active user. The data collected for this purpose includes your browser type (e.g. Firefox) and the email address connected to the account you’re using. This allows us to track user activity and improve our software.

**We do not store the Content you send for review when using our Apps and Extensions, except:**

When you use our [Editor](http://languagetool.org/editor) and the Editor integration in our apps for Windows, Mac, Android, and iOS, the following applies:

* When you use the Editor, we store the text Content you edit there to enable you to access your Content in the future. When you choose to delete a document, your deleted document will first be moved to the Recycle Bin. They are not permanently removed from our system until they are also deleted from the Recycle Bin.
* The storage takes place on servers in Germany at Amazon Web Services EMEA SARL, Niederlassung Deutschland, Marcel-Breuer-Str. 12, 80807 Munich, Germany.

### _Collected When You Use the LanguageTool Website_

When you use our Services on the [LanguageTool website](https://languagetool.org/), we may collect any of the personal data above depending on your use of our website. In addition, we will collect and store your Content (e.g. any text or document(s)) you share with us on our website, and any personal data contained in the Content.

### _Collected When You Use Our “Statistics” Function_

We may provide a statistics function for certain Services, which includes aggregated usage figures (e.g. number of words and error corrections) related to your account for at least the last 12 months. Statistics data is only collected for logged-in users and contains account-specific statistics of spelling mistakes, grammatical errors, writing activities, etc. You can disable collection of Statistics data any time in your account settings.

### _Collected About You From Third-Party Sources_

If you choose to sign up with LanguageTool using certain third-party log-in services (such as Apple, Facebook, or Google) you will provide us or allow the log-in service to provide us with your personal data, such as your email, name and/or username, if available, and any other personal data specified by that third-party log-in service. In some cases you may consent to share other personal data associated with your account with LanguageTool for this purpose, such as your profile picture, or your city and country. For more information about the personal data shared with LanguageTool, please see the third-party log-in service's (Facebook or Google) privacy policies.

As stated in Part One, we use analytics services such as Google Analytics and Amplitude to collect and process certain analytics data when you use our Services. These services may also collect information about your use of other websites, apps, and online resources. For more information about our use of these services, please see Part One and our Cookie Policy. In addition, you can learn about Google's practices by going to https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

### _Provided by You When You Communicate with Us_

When you contact us for more information about LanguageTool or for customer support, we will collect and store your name, email address and the contents of your message to us, including any other personal data that you choose to provide.

If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will collect your email. When we send you emails, we may track whether you open them to learn how to deliver a better customer experience and improve our Services. You may unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any newsletter email you receive.

We may also collect your email and any other personal data you may provide to us when you respond to surveys or questionnaires we send for research purposes or as part of our Services, or when you provide feedback.

### _Collected When You Sign Up for a Team Plan_

When you sign up for our premium Services under a Team Plan, we collect personal data from Team Plan Owners, Administrators, Editors, and Members (as defined in our Service Terms) necessary to administer and operate the Services.

If you are a Team Plan Owner, we collect your first and last name and email address. You also have the option to provide us with your phone number, company name, Business Tax Identifier, and address. As Team Plan Owner, you may invite other individuals to join the Team Plan as either an Administrator or Writer. In such a case, we use your name on the email invitation to Administrators, Editors, and Members added by you. Payment information, such as card number, is collected and processed directly by our third-party payment processors as noted above.

If you are an Administrator, Editor, or Member, we collect your email address from the Team Plan Owner to send you an invitation to join the Team Plan. To join a Team Plan, you will need to register an account with LanguageTool.

When you register for a Team Plan and use LanguageTool under a managed Team Plan account, we process any personal data we collect as described in the LanguageTool Business Data Processing Agreement available at [https://languagetool.org/legal/dpa](https://languagetool.org/legal/dpa) (“LanguageTool DPA”). For Team Plan customers only, in the event of a conflict between the terms of this Privacy Policy and the LanguageTool DPA, the LanguageTool DPA terms apply.

Our Uses
--------

We use the personal data we collect about you to provide the LanguageTool services and features you choose to use. We also use the personal data we collect about you for the purposes stated in the How We Use Your Personal Data section in Part One of this policy, with one important exception: **LanguageTool does not use inputs from any user (Individual, Team Plan, or Business) to train its language algorithms or models**. This is a default setting in LanguageTool that does not require an opt-out or any action by the user.

For UK and EEA residents, please see Additional Terms For European Economic Area And UK Residents in Part One of this policy for our lawful basis for processing your personal data for the purposes we describe.

How We Share Your Personal Data
-------------------------------

In addition to the [How We Share Your Personal Data](#part-one-how-we-use-your-personal-data) section in Part One, when you use LanguageTool below are the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of PersonalData** | **Examples of Personal Data We Collect** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom We May Share this Personal Data:** |
| Profile or Contact Data | * First and last name<br>* Email<br>* Country location<br>* Billing address (if provided) | * Service Providers |
| Payment Data | * Card holder name<br>* Payment card type<br>* First 6 and last 4 digits of payment card | * Service Providers |
| Commercial Data | * Purchase history<br>* Consumer profiles | * Service Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Online Identifiers | * Unique identifiers such as account name and passwords | * Parties Users Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| Device/IP Data | * IP address<br>* Device ID<br>* Domain server<br>* Type of device/operating system/browser used to access the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Web Analytics | * Browsing or search history<br>* Web page interactions<br>* Referring webpage/source through which you accessed the Services<br>* Non-identifiable request IDs<br>* Statistics associated with the interaction between device or browser and the Services | * Analytics Providers |
| Third-Party Login Data | * Email<br>* Name and profile picture | * Service Providers |
| Consumer Demographic Data | * Postal code<br>* Education level | * Service Providers |
| Geolocation Data | * IP-address-based location information (approximated) | * Advertising Providers<br>* Analytics Providers |
| Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide | * Identifying information in emails or letters you send us<br>* Identifying information in the content of the document(s) you share with us<br>* Specifically for proofreading services: any identifying information you share with us to help provide services to you | * Service Providers |

Provided below are the locations of third party recipients with whom we share your personal data with:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Activity** | **Recipients** | **Location** |
| Visiting our website | Data processors engaged by us, such as advertising companies and hosting providers. | Germany, USA, Ireland |
| Using our Services | Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers and providers of plagiarism software. | Germany, USA, Ireland |
| Customer service or otherwise corresponding with you | Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers and providers of CRM software. | Germany, USA, The Netherlands, Ireland |
| Other general purposes | Subcontractors or service providers such as auditing companies, consulting and law firms, and insurance companies; Data processors engaged by us, such as hosting providers; Relevant authorities | Germany, USA |

**Data Retention**
------------------

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, LanguageTool retains personal information about you for as long as you have an open account with us, as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for. In some cases, we retain personal information for longer and for other legitimate purposes, including if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, enforcing and preventing violations of our Terms, to fight spam, protecting or defending our rights, property and users, to resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form, where that information would not identify you personally. Applicable storage periods are determined on a case-by-case basis. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider applicable legal requirements, the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes we process your personal information for, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means. For example, we retain account information like your account email address for as long as your account is in existence, because we need it to operate your account.

Deleting Your LanguageTool Account
----------------------------------

If you would like to delete your LanguageTool account, you can do this directly by going to "My Account" in "Settings.” If you choose to delete your account: (1) all of your account information will be deleted from LanguageTool, 2) all your uploaded text, documents and order details will be deleted automatically; this is irrevocable, and you can never use or enter this account again; 3) we will no longer have access to your documents. This means we cannot deal with possible complaints, as we cannot address complaints from deleted accounts.

If the GDPR, US State privacy laws, or other privacy law grants you the right to have your personal data deleted entirely from LanguageTool and you want to exercise that right (or any other privacy right), please read Part One of this policy for how to submit your request.

Cookie Policy
-------------

To view our Cookie Policy, [click here](https://languagetool.org/legal/cookie-settings) .
